Bruce Bassett papers relating to Jacques Lipchitz
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Other Projects, 1961-2000, Series 6:; (Boxes 35-40, 54-55; 5.2 linear feet)
  This series contains audiovisual material and a few paper records from projects unrelated to Jacques Lipchitz that were also found among Bruce Bassett's papers. Other projects by Bruce Bassett include audiovisual recordings from projects about Isamu Noguchi, Sidney Lifchez, Auguste Rodin, the Storm King sculpture center, IBM, and others, listed below. The Lifchez documentary is well-documented, but records of other projects in the series are incomplete and fragmentary. Also found are projects by others, including a draft of a screenplay, two news films of John F. Kennedy, and several other film titles. The films Dream on Monkey Mountain and Man Is My Name were made by others but were produced or aired by NBC, where Bassett worked, and he may have been involved in their production or broadcast.
  - Projects by Bruce Bassett (Box 35)
    - A House for Someone Unlike Me with Sidney Lifchez (Box 35)
      - Finished Version, 1984, (1 videocassette: U-Matic, 2 duplicate videocassettes: VHS) (Box 35, Item 1)
      - 15-minute Version, 1984, (2 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 35, Item 2)
      - Camera Tapes 1-18, 1984, (18 of 25 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 35, Item 3-20)
      - Camera Tapes 19-25, 1984, (7 of 25 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 36, Item 1-7)
    - IBM Project (Box 36)
      - The Massey Ferguson Project, 1983, (3 film reels: color negative, internegative, and soundtrack) (Box 36, Item 8)
        (Color negative can contains film lab records)
      - Interactive Marketing Project, 1982, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 36, Item 9)
      - Computer Search and Retrieval Instructions, undated, (1 sound tape reel and paper file) (Box 36, Item 10)
      - Interviews, 1982, (1 sound cassette, 2 annotated, empty cassette cases) (Box 36, Item 11)
      - Unidentified Video, Reels 3 and 4, 1986 June 17, (2 videoreels: 1 in.) (Box 37, Item 1-2)
    - Isamu Nogochi Project (Box 37)
      - Sound Rolls 1-3, 1978 September 12-15 (Box 37, Item 3-5)
      - Momo Taro, 1979 January 4, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 37, Item 6)
      - Detroit Fountain, circa 1978-1979, (1 sound cassette) (Box 37, Item 7)
      - Honolulu Rolls 2, 5, and 7, circa 1978-1979, (4 sound cassettes) (Box 37, Item 8-10)
        (2 cassettes are marked "roll 2")
      - First Half, Soundtrack, undated, (1 film reel: soundtrack) (Box 37, Item 11)
      - Unidentified Video, undated, (1 video reel: 2 in.) (Box 37, Item 12)
        (Label reads "1-12 Lipchitz, 13-24 Noguchi")
    - Rodin-related Interviews (Box 38)
      - Jean Bernard, undated, (2 sound cassettes) (Box 38, Item 1)
      - Jean Dubos, undated, (1 side of 1 sound cassette) (Box 38, Item 2)
      - Ernest Menten, undated, (3 sides of 2 sound cassettes) (Box 38, Item 3)
      - Jean Dubos and Ernest Menten, undated, (1 side of 1 sound cassette) (Box 38, Item 4)
      - Pierre Vivant, 1981 January 22, (1 side of 1 sound cassette) (Box 38, Item 5)
      - Cecile Goldscheider of the Musée Rodin, 1979, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 38, Item 6)
        (In French)
      - Kirk Varnadoe, 1980 May 14, (1 sound cassette) (Box 38, Item 7)
      - Pierre Vivant, undated and June 1979, (7 sound tape reels) (Box 38, Item 8)
        (Identified within recordings as camera reels 315, 316, 318, 320, 322, 326, 357; location of camera reels unknown)
      - Pierre Vivant, 1981 May 10-11, (2 sound cassettes) (Box 38, Item 9)
    - Sculptors at Storm King, 1992-2000, (5 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 38, Item 10)
      (Includes multiple versions; also known as Peter Stern's Storm King)
    - Peter Stern Interview, 2000, (1 videocassette: VHS, silent) (Box 38, Item 11)
    - Book of Kells, 2000, (2 videocassettes: VHS, 1 videocassette: Betacam SP) (Box 38, Item 12)
    - Citibank Commerical, undated, (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 38, Item 13)
    - Matteo Ricci, 1991, (1 film reel) (Box 38, Item 14)
    - Unidentified Sound Cassette, undated, (1 sound cassette) (Box 38, Item 15)
  - Projects by Others (Box 39)
    - Buffalo Rock, undated, (1 film reel) (Box 39, Item 1)
    - Eames and Lipchitz, undated, (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 39, Item 2)
      (Contains films by Charles and Ray Eames and copy of Bassett's Lipchitz film)
    - John F. Kennedy News Films (Box 39)
      - President Kennedy's News Conference #12, 1961 June 28, (1 film reel) (Box 39, Item 3)
        (Contains transcript)
      - Conversation with President Kennedy, 1962 February 7, (2 film reels; oversized reels in Box 55) (Box 39, Item 4)
    - Man is My Name by Pierre Dominique Gaisseau, 1969-1970, (1 film reel; oversized reel in Box 55) (Box 39, Item 5)
    - The Man with Two Sides to His Head by Anthony Cave Brown (Box 39)
      - Draft of Screenplay, undated, (3 of 5 folders) (Box 39, Item 6)
      - Draft of Screenplay, undated, (2 of 5 folders) (Box 40, Item 1)
      - Research, undated (Box 40, Item 2)
    - NBC Experiment in Television: Dream on Monkey Mountain, part 2, 1970, (1 film reel; oversized reel in Box 54) (Box 40, Item 3)
  - Oversized film reels, Conversation with President Kennedy (2 film reels from Box 39, item 4) (Box 54)
  - Oversized film reel, Man Is My Name by Pierre Dominique Gaisseau (from Box 39, item 5) (Box 54)
  - Oversized Unidentified Video (from Box 37, item 12) (Box 55)
  - Oversized film reel, NBC Experiment in Television: Dream on Monkey Mountain, part 2 (from Box 40, item 3) (Box 55)